Dick Johnson Is Dead is a documentary film directed by Kirsten Johnson.
With this inventive portrait, director Kirsten Johnson seeks a
way to keep her 86-year-old father alive forever.
Utilizing moviemaking magic and her family’s dark humor, she celebrates Dr.
Dick Johnson’s last years by staging fantasies of death and beyond.
Together, dad and daughter confront the great inevitability awaiting us all.
Self, played by Richard Johnson.
Self, played by Kirsten Johnson.
Self, played by Isla Sierck.
Self, played by Jed Sierck.
Self, played by Felix Torres.
Self, played by Viva Torres.
Dick Johnson Is Dead is a 2020 American documentary film directed by
Kirsten Johnson and co-written by Johnson and Nels Bangerter.
The story focuses on Johnson's father Richard, who suffers from dementia, portraying
different ways—some of them violent "accidents"—in which he could ultimately die.
In each scenario, the elderly Johnson plays along with his
daughter's black humor and imaginative fantasies.
The film premiered at the 2020 Sundance Film Festival, where it won the
Special Jury Award for Innovation in Non-fiction Storytelling.
It was released on Netflix on October 2, 2020.
The film explores themes of dying and death, biography, alzheimer's
disease, stuntman, father daughter relationship.
The tone is dark.